Guide to the Jim Kobs papers, 1954-2015 and undated RL.11721
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings and Speeches, 1969-2015 and undated; 6
  - Speeches and Articles, 1969-2015 and undated; 16
    - Helene Curtis seminar, 1981 (Box 29)
    - Honeywell speech, 1983 (Box 29)
    - Houston Direct Marketing Day, 1978, 1985; 2 folders (Box 29)
      1978: first book speech; 1985: keynote, Agency President speech
    - Houston speech, 1975 (Box 29)
      DMMA spring conference
    - Hudson Valley Direct Marketing Association, 2004 (Box 29)
      Meet the Masters interview session
    - IBM private seminar, 1981 (Box 29)
    - IBM seminar, 1982 (Box 29)
      How to Reduce Selling Costs and Increase Profits with Direct Marketing
    - Idea Factory, 1987 (Box 29)
      50 Nifty Ideas for Direct Marketers
    - Indiana seminar, 1979 (Box 29)
      Profitable Direct Marketing
    - Industrial mail, 1969 (Box 29)
      The One/Two Punch for Improving Direct Mail Results
    - Informatics talk, 1984 (Box 29)
    - Inside Direct Mail interview, 2000 (Box 29)
    - Insurance and Financial Services talk, 1996 (Box 29)
    - International Direct Marketing Symposium, 1981-1984; 2 folders (Box 29)
      1981: How to Reduce Selling Costs and Increase Profits with Direct Marketing; 1984: Business Direct Marketing in 1990 and How to Get Ready For It
    - International Game Show, 1973 (Box 29)
    - Japanese study group, 1983-1984 (Box 29)
      Ajinomoto MMS Marketing Study Team
    - Jay Lipe (The Strategist) interview, 2000 (Box 29)
    - Jim Kobs speech handouts, undated (Box 29)
      Advertising examples, sample forms, etc.
    - Kansas City Direct Marketing Association, 1990 (Box 29)
      Advanced session #5: Creative
    - Kansas City Direct Marketing Day, 1984 (Box 29)
      Keynote, Direct Marketing Yesterday Today and Tomorrow
    - L.A. Direct, 1991 (Box 29)
    - Los Angeles talk, 1984 (Box 29)
      Direct Marketing Club of Southern California dinner meeting
    - Los Angeles talk, 1976 (Box 29)
      DMMA spring conference: How to Launch a Multi-Media Program
    - Lehigh Press (James Lentz), 1988 (Box 29)
      Agency Executive speech
    - London speech, 1984 (Box 29)
      British Direct Marketing Association; Direct Marketing Update '84
    - MAC (Mail Advertising Club of Chicago) copy workshop, 1973 (Box 29)
      Renamed Chicago Association of Direct Marketing (CADM)
    - Mailorder Association of Nurserymen, 1984, 1993; 2 folders (Box 29)
      1984: Book talk, client case studies; includes text of earlier article: Direct Marketing in the Seventies; 1993: Marketing Strategies for Maximum Growth
    - Marketing Council, 1978 (Box 29)
      Making Offers Work Better for You
    - Marketing workshop, 1975 (Box 29)
      Sponsored by CADM; talk on offers
    - Maximarketing book review, 1994 (Box 29)
      Review of Beyond Maximarketing, third book by Stan Rapp and Tom Collins; review appeared in DM News
    - MEA workshop, 2003 (Box 29)
      Marketing Educators Association; presentation of Interactive, Direct, Multi Channel Marketing and All That Jazz
    - Midwest Direct Marketing Association, 1984 (Box 29)
    - Minnesota, Business/Professional Advertising Association, 1984 (Box 29)
    - Montreux, Marketing Strategies, 1988 (Box 29)
    - Motorola talks, 1993 (Box 30)
      The Power of Direct Marketing; The Future Is Now; interview
    - Multi-Media Marriage, 1974-1976 (Box 30)
    - NCDM (National Center for Database Marketing), 1997 (Box 30)
      Talk with Dick Shaver, CNBC
    - New England Direct Marketing Association, 1988 (Box 30)
    - New England Direct Marketing Day, 1983 (Box 30)
    - New York Direct Marketing Day, 1977-2000; 9 folders (Box 30)
      1977: Consumer panel; 1980: 50 Ideas; 1987: Elements of Executing a Plan (panel); 1989-1998: Marketing strategies; 2000: Marketing and Internet Strategies
    - New York forum, 1989 (Box 30)
    - New York University, 1976-1985; 4 folders (Box 30)
      1976: Offers; 1979: A New Marketing Discipline; 1983: New Electronic Media, Advanced Seminar; 1985: Creative
    - Northwestern University, 1985-1989; 4 folders (Box 30)
      1985: Business Direct Marketing; 1987: Direct marketing course; 1988-1989: Graduate student talk
    - Norway seminars, 1984 (Box 30)
    - Offers--New York training, 1985 (Box 30)
    - Offers--Target Marketing, 1994 (Box 30)
      The Last Word on Offers
    - Ohio Direct Marketing Day, 1977 (Box 30)
      Creativity and Testing
    - Ohio Valley Direct Marketing Club, 1982 (Box 30)
    - Orlando Direct Marketing Day, 1987 (Box 30)
      Agency President speech
    - Pacific Northwest Bell, 1981 (Box 30)
    - Philadelphia Direct Marketing Association, 1986 (Box 30)
      Yesterday Today and Tomorrow
    - Philadelphia Direct Marketing Club, 1979 (Box 30)
      Profitable Direct Marketing, book case histories
    - Philadelphia Direct Marketing Day, 1980-1994; 3 folders (Box 30)
      1980: Basic direct marketing seminar; 1985: Beyond the Basics; 1994: Marketing Strategies
    - Phoenix Direct Marketing Club seminar, 1982 (Box 30)
      Direct Mail and Mail Order Marketing
    - PMAA (Promotion Marketing Association of America), 1982 (Box 30)
      Direct Marketing: Be on the Leading Edge of a Sales Medium That Could Dramatically Change the Way You Do Business
    - Power Forum, 1990 (Box 30)
    - President Speech additions, 1987-1988 (Box 30)
    - Prevention Magazine, 1975 (Box 30)
      Speech on offers
    - Professors and Instructors Institute, 1981 (Box 30)
    - Professors Institute, 1982, 1987; 2 folders (Box 30)
    - Promotion Update, 1982 (Box 30)
      PMAA; Direct Marketing Can Drastically Change Your Business
    - Quill talk, 1994 (Box 30)
    - Roosevelt University, 1978, 1982 (Box 30)
      1978: The Direct Marketing Proposition; 1982: Graduate student talk on direct marketing trends
    - SAM Magazine, 2000 (Box 30)
      Kobs' Story: A veteran direct marketer tells us what works online
    - San Diego Direct Marketing Day, 1982 (Box 30)
      Interactive Telephone Marketing
    - San Francisco, 1989 (Box 30)
    - Schaeffer/DeLay profiles, 1986-1989 (Box 30)
      James Schaeffer, Marcoa DR Group; DM News article on Kobs exit from Kobs & Brady
    - Seattle Direct Marketing Day, 1987 (Box 30)
    - Seattle seminar, 2001 (Box 30)
    - Shopsmith seminar, 1982 (Box 30)
    - Signature Group talk, 1989 (Box 30)
    - South Africa teleconference, 1987 (Box 30)
      Interview with Penny Smith on direct marketing trends in America
    - Speech card files, undated (Box 35)
    - Speech case studies, undated (Box 30)
    - Speech slides (binder), undated (Box 30)
    - Spring Conference speech, 1978 (Box 31)
    - St. Louis Direct Marketing Day, 1979-1987; 3 folders (Box 31)
      1979: Book case histories; 1985: Direct Marketing Yesterday Today and Tomorrow; 1987: Direct Marketing Strategies--It's Your Move
    - Stop the plane, I want to get off!, 1972 (Box 31)
    - Target Marketing--Offers article, 1995 (Box 31)
      99 Proven Offers, Plus 3
    - Target Marketing--Picking the Right Agency, 1996 (Box 31)
    - Testing Lab, 1974 (Box 31)
    - Testing panel, 1972 (Box 31)
    - Then and Now book speech, 1991 (Box 31)
    - Tupperware, 1988 (Box 31)
      Using MIS Programs for Competitive Advantage (The Power of Database Information)
    - U.K. article, 2000 (Box 31)
      Global direct marketing--What is happening in the United States; in Direct Marketing Strategies, v.2. no.2
    - U.K. exchange talk, 1989 (Box 31)
    - U.K. seminar, 1989 (Box 31)
      Direct Marketing Centre; Beyond Basics presentation
    - University of Illinois seminar, 1980 (Box 31)
    - Vegas speech, 1979 (Box 31)
      DMMA spring conference; Bankers Life case history
    - Venture Magazine article, 1983 (Box 31)
      Kobs featured in DM Agency Buyouts: Who's Next? By Donn Selhorn
    - Washington Club, 1989 (Box 31)
      The Dichotomy of Direct Marketing: Where Is Direct Marketing at Today? Where Is It Headed Tomorrow?
    - Washington Creative Seminar, 1981 (Box 31)
    - Washington speech--Offers, 1977 (Box 31)
    - Why They Like Shopping By Mail, 1983 (Box 31)
      Appeared in DMA Fact Book
    - Wisconsin Direct Marketing Day, 1989 (Box 31)
    - Wisconsin Gift Cheese Association, 1981 (Box 31)
      7 1/2 Steps to a Successful Catalog
    - Wisconsin Seminar, 1980 (Box 31)
      University of Wisconsin-Extension course, Direct Marketing/Mail Advertising Techniques
    - Wisconsin talks, 1975-1976; 2 folders (Box 31)
      1975: University of Wisconsin-Extension course, Advanced Direct Mail Techniques; 1976: Wisconsin Center in Madison, Direct Marketing Techniques
    - Women in Cable, 1984 (Box 31)
      Driving Your Message Home
    - Women's Direct Response Group of Chicago, 1985 (Box 31)
      A View from the Top: Direct Marketing Yesterday, Today and Tomorrow
    - ZIP/Target Marketing, 1983 (Box 31)
      Guest editorial: It's the 3R's (reputation, results, respect)
  - Writings--Book Files, 1963-1992 and undated; 17
    - Profitable Direct Marketing--1st edition--Preface, ch. 1-8, 1963-1978 and undated; 15 folders (Box 31)
    - Profitable Direct Marketing--1st edition--Ch. 9-21, Appendix, 1963-1978 and undated; 22 folders (Box 32)
    - Profitable Direct Marketing--2nd edition--Ch. 1-21, Appendix, 1978-1992 and undated; 27 folders (Box 33)
  - Writings--Published Work, 1974-1987; 18
    - 24 Ways to Improve Your Direct Mail Results, 1974 (Box 34)
    - Marketing Strategies for Maximum Growth, 1987 (Box 34)
    - Profitable Direct Marketing, 1st edition, 1979 (Box 34)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1975-1998 and undated; 7
  - 25 Mistakes You Don't Have to Make and 25 Winners to Copy, 1986 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-001)
  - A View from the Top, undated (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-002)
  - Basic Course part 1: Planning a Direct Marketing Program, undated (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-003)
  - Basic Course part 2: Objectives and Offers, undated (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-004)
  - Basic Course part 3: Copy and Creative, undated (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-005)
  - Basic Course part 4: Testing and Multi-Media, undated (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-006)
  - Boston Keynote Address, 1983 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-007)
  - Bringing Together the Best in Strategy and Execution, 1985 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-008)
  - Business Direct Marketing in 1990, 1984 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-009)
  - Consumer Acceptance Task Force, 1986 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-010)
  - Creativity: From the Basics to Beating Your Control, Part 1, 1983 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-011)
  - Creativity: From the Basics to Beating Your Control, Part 2, 1983 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-012)
  - Creativity Applied in Direct Marketing, Part 1, 1985 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-013)
  - Creativity Applied in Direct Marketing, Part 2, 1985 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-014)
  - Direct Marketing: A New Marketing Discipline, undated (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-015)
  - Direct Marketing: Yesterday, Today and Tomorrow, 1988 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-016)
  - Fifty Nifty Ideas in Direct Marketing, Jim Kobs and Bernard Goldberg, 1987 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-017)
  - Fulfilling Future Promise: New Electronic Video Technology, 1983 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-018)
  - Fulfilling Future Promise: New Electronic Technology, 1984 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-019)
  - How Direct Marketing Is Being Shaped by Sophisticated Direct Marketers, 1984 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-020)
  - Jim Kobs Catalog Conference, 1990 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-021)
  - Jim Kobs Direct Marketing Day in New York, 1989 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-022)
  - Jim Kobs DMA Spring Conference: Offers and Testing, 1989 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-023)
  - Jim Kobs, Alan Fondrow: DMA Spring Management Conference, undated (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-024)
  - Jim Kobs, Jack McNichols: DMA Spring Conference, 1989 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-025)
  - Jim Kobs, Sol Blumenfeld: DMA Spring Conference, 1989 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-026)
  - Making TV Pay Off, 1985 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-027)
  - Managing the Creative Process, 1985 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-028)
  - Marketing Strategies for Maximum Growth, 1987 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-029)
  - Offers and Incentives to Improve Results, 1976 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-030)
  - Small Computer at $7.95 Gets Gold Mailbox for RCS&S--Jim Kobs, T. Cooper, undated (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-031)
  - Telephone Marketing--Roman and Kobs, undated (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-032)
  - Timetable for the Electronic Revolution, 1982 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-033)
  - Trends and Opportunities in Direct Marketing, 1984 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-034)
  - Trends in Direct Marketing, 1984 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-035)
  - What Happened and What's Ahead--Jeffrey Hallet, Robert Kaden, 1984 (Box AV1, Audio-cassette RL11721-CS-036)
  - Old American Insurance--Social Security Kit comics support :30 commercial with Tucson tag, undated (Box AV2, Film-reel RL11721-F16-001)
  - Rapp Collins & Adler--Old American Insurance; Wards New Store Opening; answer print, 1975 (Box AV2, Film-reel RL11721-F16-002)
  - Stone & Adler television spots, undated (Box AV2, Film-reel RL11721-F16-003)
  - Marketing Strategies, Jim Kobs speech at DMIX Forum; Media to DVD transfer, 1987 (Box AV2, Video-disc RL11721-OP-001)
  - Kobs & Brady--Australia speech reel; 11:00, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11721-Umatic-001)
  - Kobs & Brady--K&B Reel; 2:00 for Montreux marketing strategies talk, 1988 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11721-Umatic-002)
  - Kobs & Brady Master Tape--First K&B Reel, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11721-Umatic-003)
  - Kobs & Brady--Montgomery Ward Legal Services Plan spots, 1987 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11721-Umatic-004)
  - Kobs & Brady--Presentation reel, 1987 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11721-Umatic-005)
  - Kobs & Brady--Spring Conference Panel TV reel, 1985 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11721-Umatic-006)
  - Kobs & Brady--Television reel, 1985 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11721-Umatic-007)
  - AT&T On the Move with MERLIN Cordless Set: How 3 busy business owners have "cut the cord" that tied them to their desks, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11721-VHS-001)
  - Britannica: Meeting the Challenges of Tomorrow; Macropedia Knowledge in Depth 27, San Francisco Southern, undated (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11721-VHS-002)
  - Kobs Gregory Passavant--Beyond the Basics Compilation, 1998 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11721-VHS-003)
  - Kobs Gregory Passavant--Spots, 1995 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11721-VHS-004)
  - Marketing Strategies, Jim Kobs speech at DMIX Forum, 1987 (Box AV2, Video-cassette RL11721-VHS-005)